Guide to the William Watson Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Watson collection
1867-1952
GEN MSS 460
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.6
(15 boxes) + 2 broadside
Chiefly correspondence, including original letters and typed transcripts to and from William Watson and other letters and transcripts concerning him; and holograph writings by Watson, including a holograph of Wordsworth's Grave and Other Poems, many single poems, and a smaller amount of other poetry collections, prose writings, and music. Also included are personal papers of William Watson; papers of Maureen Pring Watson, including drafts of a biography of her husband; photograph portraits of William Watson, Maureen Pring Watson, and other family members; and other photographs, drawings, and printed material. Also present are a small amount of papers relating to research on William Watson by John Alexander Symington, R. W. D. Holland, and Walter E. Swayze. Correspondence includes a large number of letters from William Watson to Maureen Pring Watson and to publisher John Lane. Watson's personal papers include a group of letters and documents concerning his brother Robinson Watson. Most other correspondence concerns Watson's writing and relations with his publishers; also discussed are his views on literature, his interest in his literary reputation, and his family, friendships, and social engagements.
Watson, William, 1858-1935
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded in the finding aid or on the folders. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 15: Restricted Fragile. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
WILLIAM WATSON (1858-1935)
The English poet Sir William Watson was the author of Wordsworth's Grave and Other Poems (1890), Lachrymae Musarum, written on the death of Alfred, Lord Tennyson (1892), Ode on the Day of the Coronation of King Edward VII (1902), and other political and occasional poems, poetry collections, and prose writings. Watson married Maureen Pring in 1909, and he was knighted in 1917. After her husband's death, Maureen Pring Watson lived in South Africa and the United States.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to William Watson, acquired by the library from a variety of sources. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to March 2000 have been organized into four series. Additions since March 2000 have been placed in Series V.
Series I, John Alexander Symington Purchase, consists of three subseries: William Watson Correspondence, Writings by William Watson, and John Alexander Symington Papers Concerning William Watson. Correspondence consists mostly of typed transcriptions of letters. Some transcripts are identified as prepared by John Alexander Symington. Writings are mostly poems; also present are a few prose and musical works. Symington's papers concern his purchase and sale of Watson letters and manuscripts.
Series II, Maureen Pring Watson Gift, consists of eight subseries: William Watson Correspondence, Writings by William Watson, Music by William Watson, William Watson Personal Papers, Maureen Pring Watson Papers, Printed Material, Drawings, and Photographs. The William Watson Correspondence includes letters from William to Maureen Pring Watson, typed transcripts of letters to John Lane, and other original and typed transcripts of letters to and from Watson or concerning him. Writings by William Watson include poetry collections, prose works, and a large number of single poems. Also present are inscribed title pages cut from many of his published works. Music by William Watson consists of song settings of Watson's poems for voice and piano and a few hymns and pieces for piano solo. Most song settings were composed by Watson; a few were composed by others on Watson's texts. The William Watson Personal Papers include correspondence and legal documents relating to his brother Robinson Watson and a libel case pursued against him by William Watson. Also present are other personal legal documents and several locks of hair of William and Maureen Pring Watson. The Maureen Pring Watson Papers consist of two drafts of her biography of her husband titled "England, Are You Proud?," and a small amount of correspondence and other papers, including letters from Walter E. Swayze concerning his research for a dissertation on Watson and documents relating to Maureen Pring Watson's residence in the United States after her husband's death. Printed Material consists mostly of clippings concerning Watson, with a few newspaper broadside advertisements and other materials. Most Drawings and Photographs are portraits of William or Maureen Pring Watson. Also present are photographs of other members of the Watson and Pring families. Many photographs are annotated on the verso by Maureen Pring Watson.
Series III, George S. MacManus Purchase, consists of four subseries: William Watson Correspondence, Other Correspondence Concerning William Watson, a small subseries of Writings by William Watson, mostly poems, and a small subseries of R. W. D. Holland Papers Concerning William Watson. Holland's papers relate to his research on Watson and include correspondence concerning the life of Maureen Pring Watson after her husband's death.
Series IV, Materials From Other Sources, consists of three subseries: Correspondence of William Watson, Poems by William Watson, and Other William Watson Papers. Poems include a holograph of Wordsworth's Grave and Other Poems.
In all series, most correspondence of William Watson concerns his writing and relations with his publishers; also discussed are his views on literature, his own literary reputation, and family, friendships, and social engagements. In addition to correspondents listed in folder titles, other correspondents represented in typed transcripts in Series I and II include Arthur James Balfour, Earl of Balfour, David Beatty, Earl Beatty, Arthur Christopher Benson, Augustine Birrell, Robert Seymour Bridges, Herbert Gardner, Baron Burghclere, Sir Hall Caine, Edward Henry Carson, Baron Carson, Austin Dobson, John Drinkwater, Alfred Hayes, William Holman Hunt, Richard Holt Hutton, Richard Le Gallienne, Justin Huntly McCarthy, George Meredith, John Morley, Coventry Kersey Dighton Patmore, Sir Arthur Thomas Quiller-Couch, Clement King Shorter, Thomas Humphry Ward, Sir Thomas Herbert Warren, and Robinson Watson.
Literary manuscripts appearing in all series are holographs, mostly drafts with corrections, unless otherwise described in folder titles. Multiple copies of single poems within a series are indicated in folder titles and may include variant versions. Additional versions of single poems may be appear as part of collections of poems, in clippings, enclosed with letters, or as single poems in other series.
Authors and publishers -- England; Poets, English; Visiting cards; Photographic prints; Tintypes (prints); Poets, English -- 20th Century; Holland, R. W. D.; Lane, John, 1854-1925; Swayze, Walter Eugene; Symington, John Alexander, 1887-1961; Watson, Maureen Pring; Watson, Robinson; Watson, William, 1858-1935
- John Alexander Symington Purchase, 1880-1948; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Purchased from John Alexander Symington on the Plain Fund, 1948.
  - WILLIAM WATSON CORRESPONDENCE
    - Transcriptions of Letters From WW
      - Clodd, Edward, letters dated 1892-1900, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Gosse, Edmund, letters dated 1891-1917, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Lane, John, letters dated 1906-16, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Watts-Dunton, Theodore, letter dated 1910, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Accompanied by correspondence of TWD and "Henry"
    - Other Letters Concerning WW
      - ALS from James Bryce, Viscount Bryce, to WW, 1901 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - ALS from A. E. Housman to F. C. Owlett, 1930 Oct 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "A Collection of Literary Letters Addressed to Sir William Watson," typed transcripts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "The Correspondence of Sir Edmund Gosse ... Concerning Sir William Watson ...," typed typescripts (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Transcripts, prepared by John Alexander Symington
  - WRITINGS BY WILLIAM WATSON
    - Poems
      - "Averted Doom", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - "The Congress of the Bards," galley proof, n.d.
        Also titled: "The Battle of the Bards"
      - "The Dream of Man," bound in a volume, [1891] (Box 1, Folder 10)
        With an ALS and presentation inscription from Edmund Gosse to Charles Benjamin Foote, 1893
      - "Edenhunger", n.d.
      - "Epitaph," "Loves and Hates," and "On a Deceased Author" (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - "For England" (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - "The Husbandman of Heaven (Lines Written Near the Burial-Place of Burns)"
      - "I Care Not"
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: Music, Oversize, Box 12, folder 369
      - "Kate Barlass", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - "The King Without Peer", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - "The Lighthouse of Love", n.y. Jul 31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - "Loves and Hates"
        See: "Epitaph," Box 1, folder 11
      - "Nature's Way", n.d.
      - "On a Deceased Author"
      - "On Coleridge's Christabel", ca. 1880
      - "A Patriot's Prayer," typescript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - "The Playmates", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - "A Portrait," about Sir Hall Caine and Dante Gabriel Rossetti (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - "Rapture", n.d.
      - "Reims", n.d.
      - "Retrogression", 1915
      - "The Sexes of Song", n.d.
      - "Sonnet Written in Mr. Sidney Lee's Life of Shakespeare", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - "Staggerall", n.d.
      - "Thy Heart is Mine"
        See: Music, Oversize, Box 13, folder 370
      - "Till Ireland Has Her Own" (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - "To James Bromley, Esq., of Lathom, Lancashire", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - "Tradition in Art and Letters"
      - "Who Can Tell", n.d.
      - "Wordsworth's Grave," galley proof, holograph corrections by Alfred Austin and annotations by James Bromley and WW, 1887
      - "The Yapping Cur", n.d.
      - "The Yesterdays and the Morrows: Sonnet on the Eve of the Author's Seventy- Sixth Birthday", [1934?] (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Other Writings and Music
      - "'Christabel': A Note on Some of Its Enigmas," essay on the poem by Samuel Taylor Coleridge, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - "I Care Not," song, for voice and piano, copyist's manuscript
      - "Thy Heart is Mine," song, for voice and piano, copyist's manuscript
  - JOHN ALEXANDER SYMINGTON PAPERS CONCERNING WILLIAM WATSON
    - "Sir William Watson: Bibliography," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - TLS to James T. Babb and Walter E. Swayze, 1948 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Clippings from vendor catalogs concerning WW's books and manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Maureen Pring Watson Gift, 1867-1948; Series II; 3.34; (8 boxes)
  Gift of Maureen Pring Watson, 1950.
  - WILLIAM WATSON CORRESPONDENCE
    - Letters From WW
      - Allison, J. Rhodes (draft), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Bromley, James (some fragments), 190-, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1910 Mar 3 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Clegg, R. J. (copy), 1917 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Clodd, Edward, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - The English Association (copy), 1924 Oct 22 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Fitzgerald, Mrs., 1930 Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Howard de Walden, Thomas Evelyn Scott-Ellis, Baron (draft), 1933 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Huxley, Leonard (drafts), 1923 May-Jun
      - Lane, John (drafts), 1922 May (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Mason & Freeman (copy), 1919 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Murray, Gilbert, 1914 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Northcliffe, Alfred Harmsworth, Viscount (manuscript copy), 1909 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Pritchard, Dr. (copy), 1925 Mar 17 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Ross, Charles C., 1927 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Watson, Maureen Pring, 1909-35, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41-47)
      - Williams, Dr., 1913 Jan 1 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Unidentified and fragments, 1924-28, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Letters To WW
      - Asquith, H. H. (Herbert Henry) (photograph of first page, with holograph notes by WW on verso), 1905 Jan 8 (Box 2, Folder 50)
        See also: complete original letter in Box 10, folder 319
      - Asquith, Margot, 1909 May-Jun (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Bromley, James (fragment), 1913 Sep 17 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1914-15 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Coleridge, Ernest Hartley, 1917 Jul 16 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Coleridge, Stephen (to MPW, fragment), [1910] (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Craik, Anna R., 1922-24 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Fisher, John Arbuthnot Fisher, Baron, 1914 Dec 30 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Foster, James, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Gosse, Edmund, 1916 Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Graves, Robert (to MPW, poem), 1925 Dec 29 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Hamilton, Duchess of (incomplete), 1919 Dec 8 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Harcourt, Brace and Company (to H. Howard, concerning WW), 1932 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - Lane, John, 1909, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 63)
        Includes a letter to "Mrs. [Mary?] Pring"
      - Lloyd George, David, 1933, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Pritchard, -----, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Unidentified, 1925-3[1?] (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Transcriptions
      - WW to John Lane, 1899-1919, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 67-68)
      - John Lane to WW, 1909-19, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - WW to Mrs. John Lane, 1900-09, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - WW to various recipients, 1891-1917, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - Edmund Gosse, Thomas Hardy, Lord Tennyson, and George Meredith to and concerning WW, 1884-95 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      - Concerning "Coronation Ode," 1902-09, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - Concerning "Liverpool Celebration Ode," 1907, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Other letters concerning WW, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 75-77)
        With an ALS from Walter E. Swayze to MPW concerning the some of the transcripts
  - WRITINGS BY WILLIAM WATSON
    - Poems
      - "A. C. S.: An Epitaph" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 78)
        Also titled: "Epitaph on a Famous Poet"
      - "America Once More", n.d.
      - "April", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - "The Asthmatical Dog" and "The Bobo of Baltinglass, or, The Last Wild Charge of the Babbagorgers" (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - "At a Burial", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - "Aurea Mediocritas", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - "The Ballad of Semmerwater (North Country Legend)," fragment (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - "The Ballad of the Bootmaker", n.d.
      - "Beware", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - "The Bobo of Baltinglass, or, The Last Wild Charge of the Babbagorgers", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 85)
        See also: "The Asthmatical Dog," Box 4, folder 80
      - "The Bridals at Art's Altar", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - "Callow Love" (3 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - "The Caprice of the Gods", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - "The Cathedral Music", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - "Cease, Foolish Rosebud" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - "The Changeful Voices", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - "Cloutarf", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - "The Clydesdale Creed", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - "Counterfeit Summer", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - "Cross Brow, Ambleside" (2 copies), 1923 Jan 16-29
      - "The Deathless Blacksmith" (2 copies), 1909, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - "Dedication", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
        First line: "From Milton and from Shakespeare I learned more"
      - "Dedication" (3 copies), 1921 Apr, n.d.
        First line: "To you, my little daughters, happy in being"
      - "The Desert Heart" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - "Disclosure", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - "A Doubtful Necessity" and "An Impossible Novelty" (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - "The Dream of Man"
        See: notes with "New Christening," Box 5, folder 148
      - "Dusk" (4 copies), 1925 May, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100)
        See also: Oversize, Box 14, folder 386
      - "Earth", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - "The Earth's Desire", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - "Earthworship", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - "The Easiest Revenge", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - "Edenhunger", n.d.
      - "The Elf-King's Daughter" (2 copies) and 2 fragments, 1921 Nov, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - "Elia's Foible", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - "Empire", n.d.
      - "England's Choice" (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - "Epitaph on an Obscure Person", n.d.
      - "Erskine Childers", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - "Estrangement", [1896?] (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - "Fairy Diet", 192[5?] Jul 25 (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - "The Fisher", 1904
      - "The Flight of Youth," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - "For a Cinerary Urn" and "The Robe of Themis" (Box 4, Folder 112)
      - "The Foresight of the Blind", 1918 Feb 14
        Date from publisher's stamp
      - "The Forsaken Lute", n.d.
      - "The Fowls of the Air" (3 copies, one with "O to Sail"), 1925 Feb, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - "A Full Confession", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - "The Furtive Visit", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - "The Gamesters", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - "The Gems", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - "Give Not to Me", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - "The Great and the Mean" (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - "A Guess in Anthropology", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - "His Splendid Defect" (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - "Hymn For the American People", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - "I Care Not" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 123)
        See also: Music, Box 6, folder 224
      - "The Impenitent Thieves", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 124)
      - "The Implacable" and "Just a Possibility" (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - "An Impossible Novelty"
        See: "A Doubtful Necessity," Box 4, folder 99
      - "In a Library", n.d.
      - "In My Life's Springtime", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - "An Insoluble Problem", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - "Ireland Unfreed," collection of poems, holograph and printed clippings, inscribed to MPW, 1921
      - "January Down West" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 128)
        Also titled: "January"
      - "Just a Possibility", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 129)
        See also: "The Implacable," Box 4, folder 125
      - "Kate Barlass", 1925 Jan 27 (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - "Lady Coy's Refusal" (5 copies, including typescript), 1929, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 131)
        See also: Music, Oversize, Box 12, folder 374
      - "Lakeland Once More" (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - "The Lark and the Thrush" (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - "The Lighthouse of Love"
        See: Music, Oversize, Box 12, folder 375
      - "Lines in a Volume of the Author's Poems Sent to M. R. C." (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - "Lines Read by the Author at the Dickens Centenary Celebration in New York" (3 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - "The Lost Souls", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 136)
        See also: notes with "New Christening," Box 5, folder 148
      - "The Lure" with another copy on verso, typescript with holograph corrections, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - "The Lute-Player", 1881
        See also: Music, Box 6, folder 225, and Music, Oversize, Box 12, folder 376
      - "The Lute's Constancy", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - "Lyrics and Romances," collection of poems, [ca. 1925] (Box 4, Folder 139)
        Also titled: "Poems Brief and New"
      - "The Marble Fountain" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - "March", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 141)
      - "Mastery", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 142)
      - "Maureen Astore" (2 copies), 1909 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - "The Mounds in the Mead," 2 drafts (Box 4, Folder 144)
        Also titled: "The Mound in the Meads"
      - "The Muse in Exile", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - "My Irish Moorings", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 146)
      - "My Lord Pinchbeck", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 147)
      - "New Christening" (3 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 148)
        Appended and on versos are two additional copies, a fragment of an unidentified poem, and notes concerning "The Dream of Man" and "The Lost Souls"
      - "A New Nursery Rhyme", n.d.
      - "The Night and the Morning" (Box 5, Folder 149)
      - "1915", n.d.
      - "The Noblest Victory", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 150)
      - "O Placid Moon", n.d.
        See also: Music, Oversize, Box 12, folder 378
      - "O Shall My Soul", n.y. Jul 28 (Box 5, Folder 151)
      - "O to Sail" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 152)
        See also: "The Fowls of the Air," Box 4, folder 113
      - "Ode in May", n.d.
      - "Ode in September" (2 copies), 1927 Oct 7, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 153)
      - "Ode on the Coronation of Edward VII," excerpt, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 154)
      - "Oh, France is the Land That Leads the Way"
        Title from first line.
      - "On a Certain Statue of Liberty," "On a People's Poet," and "To One Bereaved"
      - "On a People's Poet", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 155)
        See also: "On a Certain Statue of Liberty," Oversize, Box 14, folder 389
      - "On a Portrait" (2 copies), 1919 Dec, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 156)
      - "On a Surname Sometimes Hyphenated with Quiller", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 157)
      - "On Seeing Q. Elizabeth's Bed, at Haddon Hall", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158)
      - "On the Author's 55th Birthday (1913)", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
      - "One of the Fallacies", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 160)
        See also: "To a Bereaved One," Box 5, folder 191
      - "Our Land"
        See: Music, Box 6, folder 226
      - "Pan's Counsel", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 161)
      - "Peace", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
      - "Pools of Evil" (2 copies), 1925 Jan 30-31 (Box 5, Folder 163)
      - "Prelude" (2 copies), 1926 Sep (Box 5, Folder 164)
      - "The Raven's Shadow", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 165)
      - "A Recipe", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 166)
      - "The Reconciliation", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 167)
      - "Rejuvenescence" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 168)
      - "The Rival Sisters" (3 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 169)
      - "The Robe of Themis" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 170)
        See also: "For a Cinerary Urn," Box 4, folder 112
      - "St. George's, Windsor"
        See: Music, Box 6, folder 227
      - "A Sketch", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 171)
      - "The Songsters", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 172)
      - "A Sonnet to My Beloved", 1909 Dec 11 (Box 5, Folder 173)
      - "Sonnet Written Among the Westmorland Fells" (2 copies), 192[4?], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 174)
        Also titled: "Sonnet Written Among the Fells"
      - [Sonnets to Miranda], collection of poems
      - "The Stars in Their Courses" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 175)
      - "Statesmanship", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 176)
      - "The Stones of Stanton Drew" (Box 5, Folder 177)
      - "Storm in Mid Atlantic", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 178)
      - "The Stranger-Minstrel", n.d.
      - "Summer's Overthrow", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 179)
      - "The Superhuman Antagonists and Other Poems," inscribed to MPW, 1919
      - "The Tarn and the Torrent" (Box 5, Folder 180)
      - "Teach Me But Peace" (2 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 181)
        Appended to one copy: "They and We"
      - "The Terrors of Truth", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 182)
      - "They and We" (Box 5, Folder 183)
        See also: "Teach Me But Peace," Box 5, folder 181
      - "Thomas Hood", 1915